Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
Gender Insurance Company Limited's Q3
and 9 months FI 2026 earnings conference
call from the senior management. We have
with us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and
CEO of the company. Mr. Gopal
Baloachandran CFO Mr. Anand Singhi Chief
retail and government Mr. Girishnaek,
Chief Technology and Health Underwriting
and Claims. Mr. Sep Gorada, chief
corporate solutions international and
bank assurance and Mr. Goro Vura, Chief
Reinsurance, Underwriting and Claims for
Property and Casualty.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on the information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risks and
uncertaintities which could cause
results to differ materially from the
current views being expressed. As a
reminder, all participant lines will be
in the listenon mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO, ICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you, sir.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call for ICA Lombard for quarter 3 and 9
months financial year 2026.
At the outset, let me wish you all a
very happy new year and best of health
and happiness.
I would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent economic and
industry trends which has shaped the
operating environment over the past few
months. Following that, our CFO Mr.
Gopal Balach Chandran will take you
through the company's financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months. The Indian economy
recorded a GDP growth of 8.2% in quarter
2 up from 7.8 in the preceding quarter.
The expansion was underpinned by
sustained government capital expenditure
coupled with an increase in private
capex rup service activi services
activity and a rebound in private
consumption. Consumption was further
supported by easing inflation and the
GST rationalization implemented in late
September 2025.
Coming to Q3 financial year 2026, the
index of industrial production, IIP data
indicates positivity supported by
manufacturing growth, continued
infrastructure development and a
turnaround in consumer good segment. EV
bill generation and toll collections
during the same period recorded growth
of 13% and 17% YI reflecting strong
underlying economic activity. We believe
that these high frequency indicators
should auger well for a commercial line
and of segmented
by GST rationalization the automo sector
has seen a significant uptick in sales.
According to retail sales data based on
vhan registration, the auto industry
recorded a growth of 19.5% for quarter 3
2026 resulting in a total of 9.4 million
vehicles sold.
Within this private car had seen a
growth of 19.3%
translating to 1.3 million vehicles. The
two-heer segment grew by 19.2%
with the 7 million vehicles whereas
commercial vehicles grew by 22.2%.
with 1.1 million vehicle being sold.
Interestingly, the overall growth in the
vehicle sales is the highest in last 12
quarters. To add to it, this growth is
more broad-based as tier three cities
and beyond have demonstrated faster
growth in both private car and two
segments. This is also coraborated by
strong growth of 28.8% in tractor sales
for the quarter. Overall, the
acceleration in new vehicle sales for
the quarter has also led to a 7.7%
growth for calendar year 2025 with a
28.1 million units being sold.
The landmark decision of exemption of
GST on retail health insurance has
significantly improved affordability and
increased awareness.
The industry has passed on the complete
benefit of GST exemptions to the end
consumers.
This has led to an increase in policy
uptake as more customers are seeing
health seeking healthcare protection.
Here too, the growth in retail health
appears to be broad-based across markets
and it's supported by a surge in
firsttime buyers especially for tier 2
and tier three cities which is a
positive for this sector.
On the regulatory front, the government
of India took a significant step during
the quarter by introducing
forward-looking reforms in the insurance
laws with the passage of Saka Bimma Saki
amendment of insurance laws bill 2025.
While most of these amendments will have
farreaching effects on the insurance
sector over time, a few important
changes pertaining to the insurance act
are as follows. Foreign investment is in
an Indian insurance company has enhanced
from 74% to 100% thereby supporting
capital inflows enabling provisions in
the amendment act to facilitate business
other than traditional insurance
underwriting and distribution thereby
allowing insurers to offer holistic risk
management services.
Simplification of provisions relating to
investments of assets.
We are excited about these changes and
we do believe that this should be
structurally positive and would
accelerate the growth and development of
the insurance sector. This will also
facilitate ease of doing business and
provide better protection and risk
management solutions to the policy
holders.
In another significant reform in
November 2025, the government of India
formally made effective four new central
labor codes including the code on social
security 2020. Consequent to this,
benefits like gratuitity, leave and cash
etc paid on basic salary are now
required to be paid. This is the new
broader definition of wage.
We believe this changes should translate
into a more resilient workforce and
strengthen employee security over time.
This change has a one-time impact on the
financials which will be covered by
Gopal in his section.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the period ended 31st
December 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 8.7% for 9 months 2026
excluding crop and mass cell segment.
The GDPI growth at 13.3 growth stood at
13.3% for the period 9 month 2026.
Speaking on specific segments within the
industry, commercial segment recorded a
healthy growth of 14.8 8% for 9 month
2026 and 16.3% for quarter 3 2026.
This growth led by strong momentum in
the fire line which grew at 20.1% for 9
month 2026.
As mentioned above, this is driven by an
increase in capex particularly in areas
such as road, railways and renewable
energy.
The motor segment grew at 8.9% in 9
months 2026.
compared to 7.6% in H1 2026.
For quarter 3 financial year 2026, the
growth stood at 10.9% supported by
festive season demand and the positive
impact of GST rationalization. Health
segment grew at 14.2%
for 9 months 2026 with a strong momentum
of 27.6% 6% growth in quarter 3 of 2026
led by retail health which grew at 33.6%
and group health growth of 23.1%
underscoring strong demand across the
segment.
On the other hand, industry combined
ratio worsened from 113.3%
in H1 of 2025 to 119.2% 2% in H1 of 2026
indicating continued underwriting
pressure. During the same period, IC
core moved from 103.2%
in financial year 2025 to 104.0%
in H1 of 2026, reinforcing a superior
financial performance through discipline
underwriting.
The motor line of business remains a key
area of stress with the industry core
increasing from 124.8% 8% in H1 of 2025
to 128.5%
in H1 of 2026.
IC alumba demonstrated better portfolio
management in motor insurance with the
combined ratio improving from 108 to
106.9%
during the same period.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments.
For 9 month 2026, gross domestic premium
income of the company grew by 3.6%
compared to industry growth of 8.7% for
the same period.
Within this for quarter 3 2026 the
company reported a premium growth of
13.3% compared to industry growth of
11.5%
thereby improving its market share from
8.1% for quarter 3 2025 to 8.3% for
quarter 3 2026
for December 2025 in particular the
company's growth in GDPI was 16.1% in
comparison to the industry growth of
14.4% 4%
excluding cross crop and mass health the
company recorded a growth of 7.5%
during 9 month financial year 2026
against the industry growth of 13.3%
within this for quarter 3 2025 the
company record a growth of 16.4%
as against the industry growth of 20.1%.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 7.4%
and 6.8% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
respectively. While the industry grew by
16.3% for quarter 3 2026 and 14.8% for 9
month 2026,
we continue to be focused on delivering
profitable growth through disciplined
underwriting, prudent risk selection and
portfolio diversification. resulting in
the growth of fire segment by 18.8% in
quarter 3 2026 driven by 27.4% growth in
the theme segment.
Further, the company delivered a 19.3%
growth in fire compared to 15.8 industry
growth for the month of December 2025.
In the engineering segment, our growth
stood at 15.2% 2% and 13.3% for quarter
3 2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
While the industry during the same
period grew by 11.5% and 12.9%
respectively. This led to we attaining
leadership position in engineering
segment for the 9 month 2026.
On the other side, for 9 month 2026, the
company's growth for marine cargo and
liability segment was not in line with
the industry growth on on account of
portfolio rationalization. However, we
continue to maintain our leadership
position in these lines.
In motor segment for 9 months 2026, the
company record a growth of 5% whereas
the industry view by 8.9%.
While I while our growth in H1 of 2026
was only 2.2%, a rebound was observed in
Q3 2026 driven by an underlying buoyancy
in new motor vehicle sales.
Consequently, the motor segment grew by
9.3% in Q3 2026 supported by a strong
growth of 16.1% in December 2025.
Despite heightened competitive intensity
in the recent quarters, we remain
focused on profitable growth driven by
continuous expansion across distribution
channels and a more granular portfolio
segmentation.
Importantly, the company continues to
maintain it leadership position in the
motor segment with a market share of
10.7% for 9 months 2026.
The company's portfolio motor portfolio
mix of private car two-heer and
commercial vehicle stood at 53.6
25.8% and 20.6% respectively for 9 month
financial year 2026.
In the health segment the company grew
by 42% and a 13.8% for quarter 3 2026
and for 9 month 2026 respectively as
against the industry growth of 27.6 6%
and 14.2% for quarter 3 financial year
2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
Our health business delivered a robust
growth of 85.8%
in quarter 3 2026 and 44.8%
in 9 month 2026 significantly
outperforming the industry growth of
33.6% 6% in quarter 3 and 16.5% for 9
month 2026.
Our growth was fueled by new to industry
customer growth of 1.7x for quarter 3
2026 and 1.4 times for 9 month 2026.
Thus, our market share increases to 4%
in 9 months 2026 compared to 3.2% for
the same period in the previous year.
And for quarter 3 2026, a market share
has increased to 4.5%
from 3.2% for the same period in
previous year. The strong performance
has also been driven by sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
distribution capabilities across
channels.
The group health segment registered a
growth of 26.6%
and 5.9% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
2026 respectively. While the industry
grew by 23.1% for quarter 3 2026 and
12.6% for 9 months 2026.
I would now like to apprise you of
certain strategic initiatives that
continue to drive operational excellence
in customer sensit sensicity across the
organization.
The one as one call center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition towards a
digital first do-it-yourself servicing
model. In December over 60% of the total
service engagements were managed
digitally as against 38% only for April
2025. This was possible due to our AI AI
intervention through various bots which
has helped customers in adopting DIY
service modes.
This has led to improved turnaround
times, service consistency and increased
productivity. Our differentiated service
desk initiatives which we can which we
had spoken about in a previous call have
resulted in increase of a call center
NPS to 73 in Q3 of 2026 from 60 in Q1 of
financial year 2026.
Building on a one is one digital
framework, we continue to take positive
strides toward offering a seamless and
omni channel experience across our
website and the take care platform. As
you might recall, the ILCare app was
initially launched to provide a
continuum of care for our health
insurance customers. Over time, the app
has continuously evolved with new
functionaries and features, making it a
comprehensive one-stop solution for
service and sales across multiple retail
product line.
The app has now crossed 19.7 million
downloads as of December 31st, 2025,
reflecting growing customer engagement
and digital adoption.
The customer registered the the company
registered a GWP of 3.54 billion for 9
month 2026 from the IT take care app as
against 1.45 billion for the same period
last year. I take care has also made
significant progress in addressing key
customer service requirements and
delivering a seamless insurance
experience. Just to highlight for Trip
Secure Plus, our premier travel
insurance product, customers can now
independently manage claims, policy
cancellations, extensions, and
modifications through the app. These
enhancements have enabled 93%
of services, service requests to be
processed on DIY basis without the need
for manual intervention,
leading to a corresponding reduction in
support call volumes. Notably 79% of
claim intimation for trip secure plus in
December 2025 were also initiated
through take care app as compared to 22%
in July 2025.
In order to continually enhance our
efficiency levels in motor claims, we
have expanded our cashless garage
network from 13,600 plus garages in
quarter 3 2025 to 15,000 garages in
quarter 3 2026.
75.2%
of our non claims for quarter 3 2026
were serviced at PPN up from 73.6 in
quarter 3 2025 leading to a enhanced
customer experience.
In the retail segment 99.6% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days and for
motor insurance own damage segment 96.8%
of the claims were paid within 30 days
for the period ended 9 month 2026. As a
result, our NPS for H1 2026 for health
claims stood at 70 and for motor claims
stood at 69, reinforcing our position as
a customer centric organization.
In conclusion, the domestic macro
environment remains supportive with
broad-based consumption showing healthy
momentum. We remain focused on building
a sustainable long-term franchise
anchored in the strength of our
technology processes and service
architecture. Through our one team
initiative, we continue to sharpen
execution, drive consistency, and
deliver customer outcomes at scale. We
are well positioned to convert a more
supportive demand environment into a
steady high quality growth while
maintaining discipline and underwriting,
service delivery and operating
efficiency. I will now request Gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the period 9 month 2026.
>> Uh thanks Njie and uh good evening to
each one of you. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You all can access it as we walk you
through the performance numbers. Uh with
effect from October 1, 2024, long-term
products are accounted on a 1 byN basis
as mandated by a regulator. Please refer
to the investor presentation on slide 16
for a much more detailed information on
comparison of financials on N and 1 byN
basis. Now let me update on GDPI
numbers. Please note these numbers are
on 1 byN basis. The GDP of the company
was at uh 213.72 billion rupees in 9
months current year as against rupees
206.23 billion in 9 months FI25 a growth
of 3.6% 6% as against the industry
growth of 8.7%.
GDP of the company was at 70 billion
70.41 billion in Q3 FI26 as against
rupees 62.14 billion in Q3 FI25. A
growth of 13.3% as against the industry
growth of 11.5%.
Resulting in our market share to grow
from 8.1% in quarter 3 last year to 8.3%
in quarter 3 of the current year. On the
retail side of the business, GDP of the
motor segment was at rupes 33.99
billion. In Q3 FI26 as against rupes
31.09 billion in Q3 FI25, registering a
growth of 9.3%.
The advanced premium for motor segment
was at 41.26 billion rupees as at
December 31, 2025 as against rupes 39.13
billion as at September 30, 2025.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
20.44 44 in Q3 this year as against
rupes 14.53 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 40.6%.
Within this our retail health segment
registered a robust growth of 85.8%.
During the same period GDP of our
commercial line was at rupes 15.72
billion in Q3 FI26 as against rupes
14.63 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 7.4%. Our agents
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was 1 lak 50,458
as at December 31 2025 up from 14748
as at September 30 2025. Our combined
ratio on 1 byN basis was 104.2%
in 9 months current year as against
102.9%
in 9 months last year. on an N basis our
combined ratio was 103.1% in the current
year as again 102.8% in 9 months last
year
combined ratio on again 1 byn for this
quarter 3 current year was 104.5%.
as against 102.7% in Q3 last year again
on an end basis for this year quarter 3
combined ratio was 103.1
as against 102.3 in Q3 FI25
we have been talking about the impact of
CAT losses if one was to exclude the
impact of CAT losses of rupees 84
billion in 9 months current year and 94
billion in 9 months of last year the
combined ratio on a 1 byN basis was 103
3.7% and 102.3% respectively. The same
numbers on an N basis was 102.6% and
102.2% respectively.
Uh now coming to the quarter excluding
the impact of CAT losses of rupees.11
billion in Q3 current year. The combined
ratio on 1 byN was 104.3
and the same numbers on an N basis was
103%.
There were no CAT losses in Q3 FI25s and
as mentioned by Sanjiv in his opening
remarks excluding the impact of wage
code of rupees.55
billion our combined ratio on a 1 byN
basis for 9 months current year and
quarter 3 current year was 103.9%
and 103.5%
respectively.
On a n basis our combined ratio
excluding the wage codes wage code
impact was 102.8. 8% and 102.2% for 9
months and Q3 respectively. Our
investment assets during the quarter
rose to rupes 582.96 billion as at
December 31, 2025 up from rupes 562
billion as at September 30, 2025. Our
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 3.6 times at December 31, 2025 at
against 3.57 at September 30, 2025.
Investment income was at rupes 37.57
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 33.73 billion in 9 months
last year. On a quarterly basis
investment income was at rupees 12.19
billion in Q3 current year as against
rups 11.21 billion in Q3 last year. Our
capital gains net of environmental
investment assets stood at rupes 9.33
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 7.96 billion in 9 months
last year. Capital gains stood at rupees
3.17 billion in quarter 3 current year
as compared to rups 2.76 billion in 3
last year on a 1 by basis our PBT grew
by 10.8% at rupees 29.41 billion in 9
months current year as against rupees
26.53 billion in 9 months last year on
an again for the quarter on a one by
basis PBT grew by 9.4%
for the current quarter as against rups
9.6 6 billion in Q3 last year.
Consequently, on a 1 byN basis, PAT grew
by 11.3%
at rupees 22.225 billion in 9 months
current year as against rupes 19.99
billion in 9M last year. The same
numbers on an end basis for profit after
tax grew by 13.8% at rupees 22.22
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupees 19.53 billion in 9 months
last year. On a one by basis, fat
degrouped by 9.1% at 6.59 billion in Q3
current year from 7.24 billion in Q3
last year. Again coming back to N basis
VAT remained flattish at 6.8 billion in
Q3 current year from 6.79 billion in Q3
last last year. Excluding the impact of
wage code uh on a 1 byN basis PAT was
rupes 22.67 67 billion in 9 months
current year and rupees 7 billion in Q3
current year registering a growth of
13.4% and a D growth of 3.3%
respectively. The same numbers on an end
basis PAT was rupees 22.64 billion for 9
months current year and rupees 7.21
billion in Q3 of this quarter
registering a growth of 15.9% and 6.3%
respectively.
Coming to ROE on a 1 byN basis it was
19.5% in 9 months as against 20.8% in 9
months last year. ROE for the quarter 3
current year was 16.5% as against 21.5%
in Q3 FI25 excluding the wage code
impact on a 1 byN basis ROE was 19.8%
and 17.5% in 9 months and Q3 of the
current year respectively. Solveny ratio
was at 2.69 69 times at December 31,
2025 as against 2.73 times at September
30, 2025 continued to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
times. As I conclude, I would like to
state that uh we are all aligned with
our ethos of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of the policy
holders are in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any questions that
you may have. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Suprain Duta from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Um, thanks for the opportunity. My
first question is on the labor codes.
Um, you know, we understand that you
know there is a 50 cr impact from you
know the labor code changes. Just wanted
to understand what proportion of this
was recurring versus what proportion of
this was one time. You know that was the
first question. Secondly, you know
coming to growth. Now you know despite
uh the GST tailwinds um you know the
growth even on the motor side if I see
has been you know slower than what the
industry has uh witnessed and I do
understand that you know competition has
been elevated but you know the regulator
at the regulatory level has taken
multiple steps you know be it expense of
management guidelines or you know
discussions with industry you know to
reduce the competitive intensity or
bring in some bit of rationality yet we
are you know not able to see that
happen. So from here you know if I'm
taking a two to three year view what
will you know drive growth in the motor
segment for a player like you which
already has 10 11% market share you know
that's you know if you could throw some
light on that you know that would be
very helpful and lastly on the motor TP
loss ratio uh I do understand last time
there was a TP release
uh but uh you know this time it seems to
be a more normalized loss ratio Um could
we assume that you know the reserve
releases would hold and you know there
is no further release that that would
come in the fourth quarter or you know
could there be further releases that
would come in the fourth quarter you
know if you could throw some light under
the top but that would also help. Thank
you.
>> Thanks thanks thanks for those
questions. uh on the first one uh so far
as the labor code is concerned obviously
uh uh uh the impact of 55 crores uh in
that sense is one time because it's
primarily the liability resulting from
an actual valuation uh for the past
service uh cost uh in so far as uh wages
is concerned. Having said that,
obviously this code is also evolving. Uh
so hence to that extent we will have to
see if there are any more incremental
guidelines or rules that are that come
into existence. But at this point of
time this is whatever has been released
thus far. This impact of 55 crores is uh
what is the past service uh cost uh
which is more which is a complete impact
that we have taken in the financials of
quarter 3 and 9 months. And if you'd
have seen also the disclosure that we
have made uh there is an element of
roughly about 17 crores. This is the
amount of unamotized cost uh which will
kind of get uh amotized over the next 3
years and in line with again the
acturial report. Uh those are the two
numbers in so far as uh the impact of
wage code is concerned 55 crores is more
a one-time impact in the financials. 17
crores of amotized cost is something
that will get amotized over the next uh
3 years. So that's in response to the
first one. On the response to the third
question, motor third party loss ratios.
Um I think I will keep uh keep
reiterating this uh what we have told
the market is um overall motor loss
ratio range that we have spoken is
between 65 to 67%. And if you look at uh
the 9month numbers and that is something
that we keep urging that you should keep
looking at year-to- date numbers than
more quarterly outcomes. The 9 month
numbers for the current year motor
overall stands at about 66.3%. This is
both own damage and third party put
together. So it's kind of pretty much
playing out in line with the range that
one has spoken about and hence to that
extent uh uh we are quite happy with the
way how things have progressed. Your
point on any uh impact of reserving etc
etc. uh again we will keep uh stressing
on the fact that there has been no
change in any of our actual assumptions
and therefore to that extent it is not
that we have done anything specific
whether it was in the context of last
year or even for the matter of fact when
you look at the numbers from a current
year perspective um so that's in
response to the uh third one and on the
second one uh I will maybe Sanjie
>> yeah I will just uh so on the motor part
uh clearly first up we are extremely
excited with the positive environment
ment that has got created as I was
giving the briefing the quarter three
numbers the growth in number of vehicles
across private car two-heer as well as
CV which was which has been more than
19% the highest in last 12 quarters is a
very very good sign uh this increase in
number has also come with the GST
rationalization which made the vehicles
cheaper and with that coming through we
had to also realign what is required and
we also spoke about in terms of how the
combine for the market has moved in
motor from 124 which was hard enough to
128. So the realignment was a very key
piece which is what we as an
organization has done. Uh consequent to
this what we are seeing is the growth of
December in particular where we have
exceeded the market expectations. We
remain very positively driven overall as
to what motor holds for us. uh we've
closed the year with a 10.7% market
share probably a loss of uh point4 or
thereabouts as to what we had 9 months
but as we close the positivity with
which we expect even Q4 numbers to build
up on the new sales would drive growth
for us because that is the combination
which we are probably best at
overall from an environment standpoints
we do see consumption playing a big role
and in that upward mobility of a
two-heer customer seeking in private car
and thereabouts also is becoming very
clear also one more point which bell for
us is we've been a distributionled
company and the growth is broad-based
which is where they see that beyond
phove
the market growth also is coming it
again is a big positive for us and it
will help us to drive what we want to
drive as an agenda so we are overall on
motor uh very positively placed but the
realignment in wake of what the
intensity is seen is something which is
warranted and we've always maintained
that we'll never shy away from taking
those calls but a range mount 10.7%
market share where we stand we are
pretty much involved as a number one
player as a topmost player we are also
very aware of the responsibility that we
carry in the motor segment in particular
>> that's very helpful thank you
>> thank you
>> thank Thank you. Your next question
comes from the line of Sankit Kota from
Aendos Park. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh uh you see the retail health growth
85 or 86 odd percentage in the third
quarter. Um honestly it has the
unwinding portion of last year too. So
if if I do end to end comparison uh
which which is more like to like so so
the uh can you just uh spell out the
growth how how the retail health has
panned out? uh if you look on end end
to- end basis
>> we are not separately calling that out
so honestly uh to that extent I think
what we would say is that uh what we are
very excited is what I think Sanjiv
responded even on motor I think the
underlying demand on ground is kind of
pretty much playing out consequent to
some of the rationalizations that have
happened in the context of uh GST uh
that we have kind of talked about even
in the last quarter and um and hence to
that extent uh one would say that uh the
growth is very very uh uh exciting and
hence to that extent while it does have
an impact uh but honestly our sense is
uh I think broadly even if I were to
kind of uh give a number even on an end
basis I think that growth would be more
or less around the same range of between
80 to 85%. So hence it doesn't kind of
change much uh which is what we had said
what we very very excited is more the
underlying impact momentum than looking
at numbers whether on an end basis or a
one by basis
>> yeah and also you know we talking about
if you look at the numbers you've gone
on 80% plus in all three months October
November and December uh so very clearly
uh the needs for differentiating that
and talking as it is it's not a easy
commentary we talking one by hand I for
you to listen on audio itself is a
challenge. I can tell you probably you
can make more sense when you have the
script in hand. Uh but this growth and
what we have been doing over sustained
quarter also is reflected in the market
share which has increased to 4.5% in Q3.
Uh which is which clearly speaks about
the underlying momentum that uh the team
has been able to build. Uh and if your
question is do you see this momentum
probably playing out even in quarter 4
my answer would be every reason to
believe and it's dire and it's again
driven by a very good demand across
markets. So there is a play and we have
a product and we have a team which is
capable of driving this transition. If
you ask the beginning of the year did we
expect a uh 4 and a half% of market
share my answer would have been probably
it would have been a shade lower than
that. So there is tailwind which is also
helping us look uh better than what we
could have been but would we have been
far would have been 4%. So it's it's
pretty much there and we are well set.
So we at the right place at the right
time uh as far as health is concerned.
>> Uh this this I mean honestly this growth
is little extraordinary even if I look
at it from the industry um standard
point of view. Is it any particular
channel or or you which way not present
in a particular channel now exploring
the channel has contributed to the
growth.
>> So that that that I can explain you that
I can sit that's what your question was.
So see the product elevate was lost last
year July. Okay. So we had started doing
well in that and that renewal base also
comes and gets added to the book. So
mathematically plus supported by the
tailwind there's an answer to that part.
I mean I'm definitely not saying that
85% of the growth that will continue
over quarters and quarters. So
mathematically speaking the retention of
a product and the quality product is
there then you get good customers and
the retention also is very high and so
there is that part which is helping us
to drive this kind of a growth.
>> Understood. But but any any new channel
which contributed like like like maybe
you were not present in one or
>> of course our agency channel has opened
up significantly and we able to attract
lot more channels. So agency is uh
driving this growth but at the same time
even on website so we've been pretty
across channels uh but the contribution
percentage per se of what was there
would not have gone through a
significant change if you look at the
distribution pattern. So they have seen
this growth across uh channels uh Sanjay
>> uh no Sanjay the reason I'm asking is
that
>> and even and even bank for that matter
>> understood understood the reason I'm
asking this question is that is is our
payout structure to the distributor is
more skewed on n basis rather than one
by n basis and given the target
>> no no no we have absolute clarity that
even if it's long-term uh what we will
do is what comes with one by as a as a
as a team for us we continue to operate
strictly on those guidelines. Okay.
>> Okay. Understood. So basically
commission payouts are also on online.
>> Sorry to interrupt.
>> Yeah. Yeah. On that. Yes.
>> Okay. Understood. Understood. Thanks.
>> Yeah. But so it would be differentiated
to that extent that one first year would
be something and then second and third
year that obviously is the case but it
is distributed basis.
>> Understood. Understood. If if I squeeze
in one more sorry
>> sorry to interrupt sir may we request to
return to the queue for followup
questions as there are several other
participants waiting to
>> yeah yes sir
>> thank you so much our next question
comes from the line of pre Jane from
Motil please go ahead
>> uh yeah hi everyone uh just questions
>> um just a couple of questions firstly on
the motor side uh we've seen a
tremendous growth in volumes and what
I've understood is there is
premiumization trends as well. uh in
spite of that uh the uh premium growth
of the industry has uh has a decent gap
between the volume growth of the
industry as well as the uh the premium
growth what we have seen right uh so in
that sense what is causing that
disparity and have you seen any further
pricing aggression uh in Q3 with respect
to uh you know motor OD premiums given
that uh you know it was anticipated that
the growth would be there and uh the
competition intensities increased. That
my first question and second question is
in terms of retail health could you give
us some uh qualitative or some numbers
as to around uh as to what is the kind
of growth that is driving the the new
customers that are coming uh what are
they coming at you know what kind of
summers they are coming and also the
existing customers are they scaling up
the summer assured and maintaining the
premium levels or what's the kind of uh
trajectory that we are seeing
Yeah. Okay. So on the uh motorcycle
fresh uh clearly if you see the growth
has been uh broad-based uh and you see
small car these small hats cars being
sold far higher uh than any other car.
So the the volume growth may not
necessarily translate into a equivalent
uh growth in premium for the industry.
And also what is to be noted is that
this growth also is fueled by the
rationalization which happened from 28
to 18%. Which itself led to an impact on
the yield per vehicle going down. So
it's a combined uh thing and that is
where the realignment also had to be
done by us as a team to ensure that what
we pick up
overall uh from the market uh with
respect to our own motor portfolio and
also we spoke about how the H1 uh is uh
you know seeing the combined ratio
getting that's to answer the competitive
intensity that you're speaking about the
motor combined in 124 and.5 and
thereabouts had very little room to go
further down. It moves down to 128 and
if that is the kind of you know
development that comes in there is no
reason to believe that the competition
intensity has gone down and at the same
time you spoke about specific players
coming and coming out. Frankly speaking
our journey is very secular. you know we
we've got a decent understanding and we
back ourselves in terms of what we are
picking up and what we do want to do in
this motor segment in particular uh we
are uh and we have always maintained
that we are very comfortable walking
away what is not making basic sense on
the ro level for motor so we do
understand we are willing to play the uh
you know game if there's an ROE that
comes through even if it's on an
elevated combine but not in a in a in a
random man we just keep acquiring
because there's an opportunity
available. So, so that kind of a
discipline is what drives us and that's
why when the industry has moved from 124
to 128 our combined actually improved by
some a percentage and some few more
basis points in that H1 period also. So
it's it's to be taken in collaboration
while maintaining market leadership. So
uh uh further pricing aggression very
little room but we maintained that over
last couple of quarters but we are very
unfaced because our journey of how we
can slice and dice and do what makes
sense what makes sense for us uh we we
would back ourselves and we are very
confident that we'll be able to deliver
what is warranted for us as a company
on uh is that pre I hope this answers
what you're seeking on motor and on
there
>> and no
DPI is another part which I must add
>> uh to say which has made the uh yield
look what it is we have been always
expecting it but it's not come through
as yet
>> okay just one thing on the motor before
you kind of answer the retail health uh
the hatchbacks and the smaller cars uh
would you say that g given a lot of them
could be the first time buyer uh
structurally and given you you have a
large history of long history of data on
the same kind of vehicles being sold and
first-time buyers would you say that the
loss ratios or could be higher on this
segment going ahead or how should
>> this of course we can we can discuss in
detail but the uh the the long answer in
I'll make it short and clear the cars
have also started coming with much
better safety features the road also has
changed so there is a lot more the
challenge systems are getting digitized
the uh overlay in terms of investigating
what's gone wrong because there are
cameras everywhere across the country
the surveillance has increased so
there's lot more pluses there are a lot
more minuses I'm not saying it uh and
these are all the factors that we are
able to use uh to drive what we want to
drive as a team and that's the USP that
we carry right so we wouldn't be too
phased by it uh and if we do see segment
going out of hand I think our ability to
take cause probably ahead of the market
is what uh is the what is what
differentiate us uh as a team. I hope
again I'm able to put across what I'm
saying.
>> Absolutely.
>> And on the retail health
>> yeah on the retail health clearly we
have seen far more you know awareness. I
think this GST card besides of course
making it more affordable has been the
biggest marketing
you know to make the individuals and
their families to realize that health
insurance is critical and as a trend to
be very honest we do see some insured
increasing significantly we see bulk of
our customers in the range of 7 and a
half to 10 lakh sum insured so which is
a big positive also to just share with
all of you whenever a customer picks up
a higher sum insured their ability to
retain and be with us is much higher
because the quality of the customer is
much better. So yes, it's a big plus for
us uh uh as a company.
>> Thank you so much. Wish you all the
best.
>> Thank you Pish. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Your next question comes from
the line of Avin Singh from MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh thanks for
the opportunity. Uh so couple of
question. The first one is looking at
the impact of 1 by n in terms of a
combined ratios. Is it kind of a fair
assumption that the your multi-year
product has seen a very very strong
growth? If you can sort of provide some
color I mean within your retail health
what is the multi-year uh premium
shares. So that's one second uh kind of
a you know that now we are kind of have
seen nine 10 months of the year. uh so
for FI 27 uh uh if I have missed I don't
know uh you can provide some kind of a
uh you know guidance on growth as well
as on combined and related partly in
motor third party should we expect uh
you know by the time you're queue for
some reserve releases given that I mean
your I mean where your reserving are
sitting or kind of a reserve releases in
FI 22 to 24 is still pretty minimal so
is it kind of you know fair to assume
that okay the Q4C should see some motor
TP thanks
>> yeah so uh I think I'll go it on the
reverse way uh so motor third party I
think obviously uh yeah uh I think as an
industry we all have been kind of
waiting for the price announcement uh so
we'll wait and see by the time we
announce uh results for the next quarter
hopefully we will see where we where we
land um so we will keep all of you
updated on that uh on the Second piece
on uh what is it that we can expect for
the next year. I think this is something
that we had spoken even in uh as in last
quarter as in to say that I think given
the strong growth momentum that we see
kind of getting rebound back to us. Uh
what we have always maintained is at a
uh at a top line or from a growth
standpoint we have tried to see if we
can be 100 to 200 basis points at a
company level better than the industry
growth numbers. uh this is cutting
across all lines and uh and that is
exactly what possibly you would have
seen uh getting exhibited in quarter 3
uh for us uh in terms of where we our
growth were viz with v the industry
growth and even more specifically if you
would have seen even for the month of
December I think we have had an
outperformance v the overall industry
numbers so therefore that's something
that we would endeavor even as we head
into given the strong growth momentum
that one is seeing on ground and hence
to that extent that is what we would
kind of pencil in in terms of trying to
continue to gain in the incremental
market share on combined more important
than the combined I think what we have
largely spoken is to try and see if we
can continue to sustain delivering roses
in that in that range of 18 to 20% even
if you would have seen the numbers for
the 9 months it's been roughly around
19% thereabout so hence to that extent
uh in that range of 18 to 20% so that's
something that we what we would look
forward again when you look at uh how we
would want to play out even for the next
year uh from an roe standpoint uh to
your first point I I think it is high
singledigit number in terms of the
proportion of long-term uh uh premiums v
the total premium that we underwrite. Um
but um I think the only thing that we
would keep urging is uh I think even as
I was as I was reading the transcript I
did realize there are so many numbers on
an end and a one by basis across various
parameters. Um so hence to that extent
if you ask us ideally on a consist this
will actually kind of continue for even
maybe for the next three quarters
because while while quarter 3 of this
year onwards now we everything is on a
one by end but still there will always
be a factor of the first question that
was being asked in terms of what is the
impact of acred of last year in this
quarter and so on and so forth. So hence
to that extent a far better reflection
is to keep looking at numbers on an end
basis and there if you'd have seen our
combined for quarter 3 has actually been
better. I think if you look at quarter 3
of last year our combined was roughly
about 102.3%.
and this number on an end basis for
quarter three the current year super I
just want to interject and make this
point and uh we had said that also when
one buy came in as a company uh we don't
want to confuse at any point of time
economic value to accounting you know we
very clear so we have uh uh in all our
conversations with our team and key
personnels who are involved uh we only
discuss on ends because that is the true
value which will get embedded in the
comes the what comes because of the uh
accounting part is just an outcome for
us and that is the real value uh you
know value that we can add even our
budgets for that matter if you have to
share are all taken on end basis uh uh
because that's how portfolio can be
picked up in the right manner and even
cash flows can get generated otherwise
the tendency to make it shorter and
shorter would erode value over long term
sorry Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nidesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh sir,
can you share the share of uh new uh in
the motor segment? What is the new and
what is uh old vehicles?
I'm trying to understand whether the
market share trends are more uh the
market share trends how they are shaping
up in both these segments are we have we
lost market share in the new side that
is reflecting into lower growth or or
it's in both both segment our market
share trends are broadly similar
>> so so n just for the benefit of all of
you I'll give you two numbers uh one is
in terms of mix for quarter 3 new is
roughly about 35% renewal is about 65
uh and if you see this numbers for 9
months new is about 33 and renewal book
is about 67. So in that sense relatively
for quarter 3 uh the mix is about uh 35
and 65 but more important than the mix
if you ask us I think the point that we
have been talking about given the
underlying growth momentum kind of
playing out with respect to new vehicle
sales and there again in the same order
as in I will give you Q3 numbers first
our new growth has been 12.4% 4%. Uh and
our old growth has been 7.7%.
Translating to an overall growth in
quarter 3 in motor for asset about 9.3.
These same numbers if you look at it on
a 9-month basis the new growth was has
been 2.5%. The reual growth has been 6.2
translating an overall growth of 5%. So
this is exactly the point that we have
been talking about. I think what we are
seeing is clearly an underlying strong
growth momentum coming coming in with
respect to new vehicle sales. Having
said that, that does not mean that for
us uh renewals/ retentions are not
important. I think that's equally very
very important. But what we have been
able to leverage is a combination of
both the underlying growth momentum with
respect to new vehicle sales and then of
course the continued focus on improving
retention as well.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And uh the fact that
the 9 month average is uh when we talk
about new is 2.5 and old is 6.2 2 while
for the Q3 uh the number goes the other
way where the new is the growth has been
led by new and as in the past Gopal has
been briefly all new has its own set of
expenses that comes but a better loss
ratio and that consequent to that it
will have its uh impact but will have a
long-term value creation for us as a
company. uh in the past for the quarters
that we done always was driven by old
growth and if you go back to our scripts
that we have said we have said our
growth is driven by old so that's a big
transition it's a big plus overall for
us and we have been able to obviously
garner more new uh in the market uh
which has helped us to get this kind of
a growth
>> sure secondly if you can share the loss
ratio in health uh segment wise
>> yeah I was just waiting for somebody to
But anyway uh so uh on uh on uh group
health uh I'll first give the quarter
three numbers and then the 9 month
numbers. First I'll give you the Q3 and
9 month numbers of last year. Group
health uh last year was about 97.2
and uh this number for 9 months of last
year was 97.7.
uh the same group health numbers for
quarter 3 this year was 90.7
and 9 month numbers is 93.2
for retail indemnity that's the other
number that generally gets asked for uh
this again quarter 3 last year retail
indeinity loss ratio was 65%.
This number 9 months was 69.1.
For the current year quarter 3, retail
indemnity loss ratios are 63.1.
9 month loss ratio numbers of 67.3. So
again if you look at uh what we have
been telling the market is on corporate
health or group health generally we have
maintained that we are quite comfortable
running at the book with the mid90s
that's being the that's the threshold
that we have spoken about on the
corporate health and that's exactly how
it has played out on a 9-month basis and
even retail health I think the range
that we have generally spoken to the
market is to try to see if you're able
to run the book at a range between 65 to
70%. I think what we are quite excited
with is the way how the growth in the
book has played out and the fact that we
have kind of largely seen maybe couple
of renewal cycles play through on the
new product that we kind of launched
last year. I think the good news is I
think the experience that you are seeing
on ground I think is kind of pretty much
holding on to the assumptions that we
are kind of princ when we kind of launch
this. So those are the two numbers uh
that I would kind of uh give give away
to all.
>> Sure. And lastly that on the health side
we are showing very strong growth. But
from a longerterm perspective how should
we uh how do we plan to manage the issue
of uh uh old lives getting subsidized by
the new lives and that lead to uh loss
ratio deteriorating over a long period
of time. uh currently we are still a
young company on the health side but as
the growth matures let's say five year
down the line how what is the strategy
to manage the overall loss ratio
so two three data points uh one is that
the penetration of retail in health in
the country overall is 5%. Okay. Uh most
of us end up looking at group health as
a funible thing for retail cover that
awareness is building up and there's a
long play available and it's also linked
to the purchasing power if we believe
that the uh GDP growth the purchasing
power the income tax curve the GST all
are living this there's a significant
road available where the uh growth of
new to the insurance or new to
protection uh will keep seeing a
significant
uh uh traction and also as loss issue
picks up which is very real and you're
absolutely spot on but at the same time
the expense and the commission of
acquisition also goes down. So there is
a counter play that comes in and uh the
the aging book in terms of how it
evolves and develops better medical
solutioning all of that what comes into
play we can talk about that when we meet
again but there is a play available and
that's why we see a future as we you
know as we go about it
and there is of course and just to add
to it there's a good preventive play
that will also become a critical factor
for each one of us in our life. So if
there was a and as a company we would uh
be very actively involved. There's so
much more available and through I'll
take care which has got good traction in
real terms. Uh we do believe that we
will play a significant role. Right now
it's all setting the policy and
admission is how we interact but that
also is progressively changing. uh there
is a good idea available uh and it's not
that sitting in our room we don't play
out and simulate as to how this port
portfolio will behave uh 2 years 3 years
5 years down the line these are part of
actual actial modelings and we are well
aware of it
>> sure sir that's it from my side thank
you
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you your next question comes from
the line of sarnav Mukharji from BNK
securities. Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh a couple of questions from my side.
First on the uh commission uh our
commission number that has increased uh
sequentially quite substantially. I just
wanted to understand that um whether
this is uh primarily due to our retail
products increasing in the mix or uh
whether you were seeing even in
commercial lines uh where you source
through maybe uh you know agents or
brokers that there has been an increase
in commission. So some color on what you
are seeing on the ground and just
because you know it's also fairly
topical that we are hearing about some
regulatory scrutiny on this side. So how
do you see the regulatory landscape
playing out? So that is the first one
and uh secondly on the group employer
employee I mean u so as you said uh that
uh the loss ratio numbers uh look fairly
encouraging. So just wanted to
understand that this loss ratio outcome
is this uh more a pricing outcome or is
this that the claims environment has
become benign which is why we are seeing
this and our growth is this like uh also
a function of the base effect because
last year I think we were uh not growing
this business. So uh is that playing out
or have you become fairly more
constructive on this business than you
were earlier? Yeah, these will be my two
questions.
>> Okay, too many things into two
questions. So, yeah,
if you two question,
>> we will obviously try and address all of
them. Uh, so on the first one, Swarnab,
I think uh again this is something that
we always call out um uh and this is
what even Sanjiv just at the end
responded to one of the one of the uh
questions. See our our business has to
be fundamentally looked at in the
context of a loss experience and cost of
acquisition. So therefore to that extent
there are always those nuances that play
out in terms of what mix of business
that you write. Uh relatively I I think
the earlier question that was asked in
terms of the mix between new and renewal
in terms of motor and when I kind of
gave out the data points clearly you
would have seen that the proportion of
uh new was much higher particularly when
you looked at the quarter 3 numbers this
will be what we had seen for the whole
of 9 months. and new inherently kind of
comes with a high cost of acquisition.
Uh and hence to that extent obviously
and more importantly if you would have
seen generally quarter three is is
typically a period of seasons. So and
more so on retail. So hence any quarter
three you go back you'll always find the
cost of acquisition to be relatively
higher than let's say what you would
have seen for other quarters. So there's
obviously an element of seasonality that
plays out when you look at the
commission numbers on an isolated basis.
But what we would keep saying is to keep
looking at it more on ideally the
overall combined ratio which for us
actually has dropped when you look at
the H1 numbers relative to the industry
adverse uh that has happened but and and
the second number that we keep talking
about is more on the overall expenses of
management. uh so even after considering
the impact of the uh wage code that I
spoke about of roughly about 55 crores
uh as at 9 months I think we are kind of
pretty much there uh in so far as the
limits that are laid down by the
regulatory guidelines so hence to that
extent that's the way we would kind of
look at u I think we are very very
conscious of what we kind of source and
very very conscious of what loss
experience and the cost of acquisition
that comes as a part of it uh to the
second point on the regulatory uh
uh evolution on this. I think honestly
we we all have to kind of wait and see
how it plays out. I think the good news
is I think from a regulatory standpoint
the regulator has been kind of
instituting the right set of guidelines
for the industry. I think a couple of
years back when they kind of introduced
this overall threshold on expensive
management that was a step in the that
was a step in the very right direction
of making sure that all companies all
cost put together are well within that
threshold of 30%. And if you look at
basis public disclosures uh roughly
there are still maybe almost 21 out of
34 players are maybe possibly met the
norm there are still a lot le list of
companies which are still in excidence
on the expense of management. So
honestly I think what we would want to
see from a market standpoint is to make
sure that every player in the market
stays within the limit on expense of
management and then honestly we will
wait for any subsequent changes that
comes from a uh uh regulatory changes
but we will be equally kind of committed
to whatever the guidelines that the
regulator lays down. Um so that's in
response to the first point on both
commission increase and what could
happen in terms of regulatory change. to
your second point on the GHI um yes it's
a combination of both I think again this
is something that we have articulated
not only in the context of GHI in
general I think what we have stayed
focused on every line is to see how we
can remain profitable and the very fact
that the loss numbers that I gave out is
a testimony to the fact that we have
been very very careful and selective in
terms of what risk do we want to
underwrite uh equally it's obviously a
combination of uh both the points that
you made it's a combination of let's say
a better price in terms of what we are
comfortable underwriting and two we have
our own in-house claims management team
I think they do a brilliant job in terms
of making sure that once the once a
group health account is underwritten how
is it that we can play a very very
important role in managing the overall
loss experience and at the same time
giving delight in so far as customer
experience is concerned which is again
reflective of the NPS scores that we
have kind of called out uh whether it is
motor or whether it is health uh so
that's so that's how the growth growth
has been reflected and again we will
continue to see that lay out even as we
head into quarter four or even for the
matter of fact the next financial year.
>> Right sir and and so just on the first
question I wanted to also uh uh check on
the commercial line side. So is there
any kind of like for where you have a
intermediary source the deal has been a
claim commission inflation anything is
possible? Honestly commercial lines in
general I think uh has been uh if you
remember I think what we have is
commercial lines we have generally have
we have our own relationship team which
acts as a direct interface in so far as
working with corporates are concerned
and hence to that extent uh obviously
relatively that cost of sourcing tends
to be very very low but at the same time
what we also write as a part of the
commercial lines is some of risk uh
which is which tends to be relatively
widely distributed and there there will
be an element of cost of distribution
but overall the point that I made when
you look at the loss experience plus the
cost of acquisition put together on the
commercial lines book that's a very very
profitable book for us and that's the
way how we look at it again rather than
looking at one element of uh the
business that we source
>> right sir got it that's very helpful
thank you so much sir
>> thank you
>> thanks
we will take the last question from the
line of Nishin Chawat from Kota Please
go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh thanks for uh taking my
question. Uh you know uh you have a very
impressive growth in retail health and
uh you know we can see an improvement in
uh you know retail uh loss ratios as
well. But uh you know as as we
understand uh you know typically the
loss ratios in retail products are
significantly lower in the first uh you
know 2 3 years and then they kind of
move up from there on. So I would have
kind of said that you know this this
this delta is because of the portfolio
mix. Is it something that the new
policies that are originated are ported
or they are they are originated under
under uh you know uh different covenants
or uh you know is is is the uh you know
is as a cohort level profitability
stable or improving or deteriorating if
you would give some color on that.
So Nish again I think I'll I'll kind of
maintain the same response that I gave
in to the earlier question which is I
think the loss ratio range on retail
health as a company that we are
comfortable running at is between 65 to
70%. So that's a number that we will
keep looking for in terms of how we are
able to stay within that uh to a large
part of in terms of sourcing. I think
honestly what we want to do is in line
with let's say some of the uh some of
the discussions that even the government
has been doing to kind of increase uh
health care or increase healthcare
penetration consequent to some of the
reforms that they have done is to kind
of improve penetration at large. So
hence I think where we are kind of
largely expanding our distribution reach
which is what we put out also as a part
of the opening transcript to say that
even on health we are do we do we are
seeing let's say an increase in tire two
tire three cities kind of contributing
and these are as we said new to
insurance uh so hence to that extent I
think so far as we are concerned uh we
would want to kind of uh continue to
expand by acquiring a lot many more new
to insurance uh customers and two and
more importantly the earlier point that
I said in terms of our ability to
continue to retain our own customers is
something that we are very much focused
on. So it will be a combination of those
two is what will continue to drive
growth in the retail scope.
>> And n just to add to what gopal is
saying see uh uh we've also transformed
our own journey right and we are a
multi-line multi-product company uh for
us whether the c customer comes from the
root of motor or from health uh we are
seeing it from a comprehensive one-stop
solution. we were uh underballed in our
offering for a number of years as far as
retail health is concerned and we know
that going in as we move along uh while
we all know that the loss ratios move
upward as we age and that's that's that
that's the truth which I don't see would
change but at the same time you also
know if you're comprehensively dealing
with this customer the motor loss issue
also goes down I mean just to share with
you so it's a very clear mix and we are
very well placed as a multi-roduct
multi-line design company. So what we
are seeing is getting a good customer on
board and then then working with them on
a lifetime profitability. So the maths
is what plays out with is what you see
because at times you will see only
health at times you will see only motor
but what we look at it is in a far more
comprehensive offering and with a 2.9%
market which was just probably 18 months
back for us to four four and a half uh
where we stand as we exit quarter three
it is just helping us to build a very
well-rounded practice. I'm not saying it
was not wellrounded but health in
particular was always in a space which
was driven by GHI and under ball on this
part. We see this as a toggling part and
we see it is a very significant play in
our scheme of thing. Uh that's why we
got invested and we we stay positive and
business it's always possible that one
or two lines will have a problem and
COVID happened health was all over the
place but motor kind of saved the day
for us. So that's the way we portfolio
gets balanced and that's where we end up
talking about what is it that we can
generate as an ROE.
>> Yeah.
>> Got it. That's that's very
comprehensive. Just uh squeezing a last
one. Uh I'm not sure if you mentioned
this but uh uh you know in case of
health uh you know there is uh you know
the the input tax credit loss because of
GST exemption. Uh so how are you dealing
with that? Are you sharing it with the
distributors or are you absorbing it? Is
that one of the drivers for higher
ratios?
>> So, so, so clearly yes, we will have to
realign our cost structure and this is
what we have done. The benefit in
totality of GST rationalization has got
passed on to the customers. Uh, and uh,
we had the benefit of as the volume
grows. Uh, for us it you know in every
line of business motor or health
economies of scale will kick in. We have
a large uh health practice as a company
which is in combined from the employer
employee as well as retail help. Uh so
so definitely we'll do what is it
required to rationalize it and serve the
customer appropriately. Yes.
>> Are you sharing it with the distributor
or I mean
>> yeah of course we had we have the
industry has shared it's not only about
us. we all of us on the general
insurance and the retail health have uh
and then the increased volume is not
impacting the income of the distributor
per se. So there is already a
counterplay which is visible uh which
can be seen in terms of the growth. So
it's not that it's one channel which is
getting impacted uh comprehensively we
are we are all able to do better
business. So yes, it's got passed on. We
have also a cost structure because uh
both part is required and today's
technology and the so much which is
going on which we have not spoken but we
can talk about it when we sit one to one
is helping us also to reduce uh cost per
transaction. uh I don't know when you
see the script which I spoke about as to
how uh we've been able to use uh you
know bots uh uh to get our digital part
of serving DIY serving significantly up
with the uh you know operator handling
it which is driven by a lot more
inconsistency and uh you know uh time
consumption which can happen. So there
is so much that is happening. So the
cost part will go down. So we will be
able to manage it on this front very
easily.
>> Perfect. That's that's that's very
reassuring. Uh thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you. Okay. Great. Uh thank you so
much for joining in and uh yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Thank you and have a great
2026. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you on behalf of ICIC
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited. That concludes this conference.
Thank you all for joining us and you may
now disconnect your lines.
>> Thank you so much. Thanks.